The Tango Lesson is a drama, music, romance film directed by Sally Potter.
On a trip to Paris Sally meets Pablo, a tango dancer.
He starts teaching her to dance then she returns to
London to work on some "projects".
She visits Buenos Aires and learns more from Pablo's friends.
Sally and Pablo meet again but this time their relationship changes,
she realises they want different things from each other.
On a trip to Buenos Aires they cement their friendship.
Sally, played by Sally Potter.
Red Model, played by Morgane Maugran.
Pablo, played by Pablo Verón.
Sally Potter, played by Géraldine Maillet.
Blue Model, played by Katerina Mechera.
Fashion Designer, played by David Toole.
The Tango Lesson (Spanish: La lección de tango) is a 1997
drama film written and directed by Sally Potter.
It is a semi-autobiographical film starring Potter and
Pablo Verón, about Argentinian Tango.
The film, a co-production of Argentina, France, Germany, Netherlands and the United Kingdom, was produced by Christopher
Sheppard in Britain and Oscar Kramer in Argentina, and was shot mostly in black and white in Paris and Buenos Aires.
The soundtrack includes original recordings of Carlos Gardel's Mi Buenos Aires querido and Ástor
Piazzolla's Libertango, two of the most iconic tangos in the history of the genre.
It also includes an original song written and sung by Potter.
The film explores themes of dance, dancer, tango,
semi autobiographical, woman director.
The tone is emotional.